<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GoodreadsResponse>
  <Request>
    <authentication>true</authentication>
      <key><![CDATA[iSAfjzMo6QHWifwOfCQvQ]]></key>
    <method><![CDATA[review_list]]></method>
  </Request>
  <reviews start="1" end="2" total="2">
    <review>
  <id>1211976204</id>
    <book>
  <id type="integer">666321</id>
  <isbn>0745630588</isbn>
  <isbn13>9780745630588</isbn13>
  <text_reviews_count type="integer">1</text_reviews_count>
  <title>Understanding Peacekeeping</title>
  <image_url>https://s.gr-assets.com/assets/nophoto/book/111x148-bcc042a9c91a29c1d680899eff700a03.png</image_url>
  <small_image_url>https://s.gr-assets.com/assets/nophoto/book/50x75-a91bf249278a81aabab721ef782c4a74.png</small_image_url>
  <large_image_url/>
  <link>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/666321.Understanding_Peacekeeping</link>
  <num_pages>325</num_pages>
  <format>Paperback</format>
  <edition_information/>
  <publisher>Polity Press</publisher>
  <publication_day>5</publication_day>
  <publication_year>2004</publication_year>
  <publication_month>3</publication_month>
  <average_rating>4.00</average_rating>
  <ratings_count>28</ratings_count>
  <description>Understanding Peacekeeping provides a comprehensive and up to date introduction to the theory, practice and politics of contemporary peacekeeping. It evaluates the changing characteristics of the contemporary environment in which peacekeepers operate, what role peacekeeping plays in wider processes of global politics, the growing impact of non-state actors, and the major challenges facing peacekeepers in the future.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Drawing on a wide range of historical and contemporary case studies, including: Afghanistan; Cambodia, Cyprus; the Democratic Republic of Congo; East Timor; El Salvador; Haiti, Liberia; Rwanda; Sierra Leone; Somalia; and the former Yugoslavia, this book develops an original conceptual framework to chart the evolution of the role of peacekeeping in global politics, and highlights the unique characteristics of different types of peacekeeping operations. Part 1 examines concepts and issues related to peacekeeping in global politics. Part 2 charts the historical development of peacekeeping from 1945 to the present. In Part 3, separate chapters are devoted to different types of peacekeeping operations: traditional peacekeeping; managing transition; wider peacekeeping; peace enforcement; and peace support operations. Part 4 looks forward and examines developments in global politics that are presenting serious challenges to the concept and practice of peacekeeping, namely, globalization, the privatization of security, preventing violent conflict, and the establishment of protectorates.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Understanding Peacekeeping will be essential reading for students and scholars of peace and conflict studies, security studies, and international relations.</description>
<authors>
<author>
<id>357684</id>
<name>Alex J. Bellamy</name>
<role></role>
<image_url>
<![CDATA[https://s.gr-assets.com/assets/nophoto/user/u_200x266-e183445fd1a1b5cc7075bb1cf7043306.png]]>
</image_url>
<small_image_url>
<![CDATA[https://s.gr-assets.com/assets/nophoto/user/u_50x66-632230dc9882b4352d753eedf9396530.png]]>
</small_image_url>
<link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/357684.Alex_J_Bellamy]]></link>
<average_rating>3.84</average_rating>
<ratings_count>55</ratings_count>
<text_reviews_count>4</text_reviews_count>
</author>
</authors>
  <published>2004</published>
</book>



  <rating>0</rating>
  <votes>0</votes>
  <spoiler_flag>false</spoiler_flag>
  <spoilers_state>none</spoilers_state>

  

<shelves>
  <shelf name="read" exclusive="true" />

</shelves>

  <recommended_for></recommended_for>
  <recommended_by></recommended_by>
  <started_at></started_at>
  <read_at></read_at>
  <date_added>Thu Feb 26 03:18:02 -0800 2015</date_added>
  <date_updated>Thu Feb 26 03:19:00 -0800 2015</date_updated>
  <read_count></read_count>
  <body>
      
  </body>
  <comments_count>0</comments_count>
  <url><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1211976204]]></url>
  <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1211976204]]></link>
    <owned>0</owned>
</review>

    <review>
  <id>1211975974</id>
    <book>
  <id type="integer">6601356</id>
  <isbn>0745643485</isbn>
  <isbn13>9780745643489</isbn13>
  <text_reviews_count type="integer">0</text_reviews_count>
  <title>Responsibility to Protect: The Global Effort to End Mass Atrocities</title>
  <image_url>https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1375677068m/6601356.jpg</image_url>
  <small_image_url>https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1375677068s/6601356.jpg</small_image_url>
  <large_image_url/>
  <link>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6601356-responsibility-to-protect</link>
  <num_pages>249</num_pages>
  <format>Paperback</format>
  <edition_information/>
  <publisher>Polity Press</publisher>
  <publication_day>1</publication_day>
  <publication_year>2009</publication_year>
  <publication_month>3</publication_month>
  <average_rating>3.73</average_rating>
  <ratings_count>11</ratings_count>
  <description>At the 2005 UN World Summit, world leaders endorsed the international principle of Responsibility to Protect (R2P), acknowledging that they had a responsibility to protect their citizens from genocide and mass atrocities and pledging to act in cases where governments manifestly failed in their responsibility. This marked a significant turning point in attitudes towards the protection of citizens worldwide. &lt;br&gt;This important new book charts the emergence of this principle, from its origins in a doctrine of sovereignty as responsibility, through debates about the legitimacy of humanitarian intervention and the findings of a prominent international commission, and finally through the long and hard negotiations that preceded the 2005 commitment. It explores how world leaders came to acknowledge that sovereign rights entailed fundamental responsibilities and what that acknowledgment actually means. The book goes on to analyze in detail the ways in which R2P can contribute to the global effort to end genocide and mass atrocities. Focusing on the prevention of these crimes and the improvement of the world's reaction to them, the book explores the question of how to build sustainable peace in their aftermath. Alex J. Bellamy argues that although 2005 marked an important watershed, much more work is needed to defend R2P from those who would walk away from their commitments and - in the words of UN Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon - to translate the principle 'from words into deeds'. &lt;br&gt;This fascinating book will appeal to students and scholars of international relations, international affairs, human rights and humanitarian emergencies, as well as anyone concerned about the protection of civilians on a global scale</description>
<authors>
<author>
<id>357684</id>
<name>Alex J. Bellamy</name>
<role></role>
<image_url>
<![CDATA[https://s.gr-assets.com/assets/nophoto/user/u_200x266-e183445fd1a1b5cc7075bb1cf7043306.png]]>
</image_url>
<small_image_url>
<![CDATA[https://s.gr-assets.com/assets/nophoto/user/u_50x66-632230dc9882b4352d753eedf9396530.png]]>
</small_image_url>
<link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/357684.Alex_J_Bellamy]]></link>
<average_rating>3.84</average_rating>
<ratings_count>55</ratings_count>
<text_reviews_count>4</text_reviews_count>
</author>
</authors>
  <published>2009</published>
</book>



  <rating>0</rating>
  <votes>0</votes>
  <spoiler_flag>false</spoiler_flag>
  <spoilers_state>none</spoilers_state>

  

<shelves>

    <shelf name="to-read" exclusive="true" review_shelf_id="922546212" sortable="true" />
</shelves>

  <recommended_for></recommended_for>
  <recommended_by></recommended_by>
  <started_at></started_at>
  <read_at></read_at>
  <date_added>Thu Feb 26 03:17:25 -0800 2015</date_added>
  <date_updated>Thu Feb 26 03:17:25 -0800 2015</date_updated>
  <read_count></read_count>
  <body>
      
  </body>
  <comments_count>0</comments_count>
  <url><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1211975974]]></url>
  <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1211975974]]></link>
    <owned>0</owned>
</review>

</reviews>

</GoodreadsResponse>
